

# Ziqi Xie

Ph.D. Candidate, Economics



6823 St. Charles Avenue. 206 Tilton Hall New Orleans, LA 70118



+1 617-820-2833



https://ziqixie.com



zxie@tulane.edu

## About me –

Zigi Xie is a Ph.D. candidate in economics at Tulane University, New Orleans, LA. He has a research interest in public economics, corporate finance, and health economics. Currently, he is researching dividend tax policy changes and VAT policy in China by using a variety of econometric models, including differencein-differences, propensity score/k-NN matching, etc.

Besides research, Ziqi enjoys playing basketball, traveling, and photographing. He played as small forward at Tulane Intramural - Chinese Basketball Team during 2015-2017.

Prior to coming to Tulane, Ziqi studied in Shanghai and Boston. He held B.A. and M.A. in economics from Shanghai Ocean University and Northeastern University, respectively.

Skills ———					
Pytho	on				
SAS					
R					
LATE	X				
STATA	4				

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamen-

tal Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

#### **Education**

2019

May 2020 Ph.D. Economics (Expected) New Orleans, LA Tulane University May 2014 M.A. Economics Boston, MA Northeastern University

June 2012 B.A. Economics Shanghai, China

### Professional Activities

Shanghai Ocean University

Financial Management Association Annual Meeting (Chair, Discussant): New Orleans, LA 2019 Chinese Economists Society North America Conference (Presenter, Chair); Lawrence, KS

2019 American Economic Association Annual Meeting (Presenter); Atlanta,

2018 National Tax Association Annual Meeting (Presenter); New Orleans, LA

### Honors and Awards

2019	Laura Bassi Scholarship Partial Award
2019	Tulane School of Liberal Arts Summer Dissertation Merit Fellowship
2019	China Economist Society Travel Subsidy
2019	Tulane Office of Graduate and Postdoctoral Studies Travel Award
2019	Tulane School of Liberal Arts J.E. Land Fund for Graduate Education
2018	Tulane Office of Graduate and Postdoctoral Studies Travel Award
2015	Research Funding, Tulane Economics
2015-2010	Fellowship & Teaching Assistantship & Full Tuition
2013	Omicron Delta Epsilon Economic Honor Society
2012	Best Graduation Thesis & Best Graduates of the Year
2011	Excellent Student Leader

### Experience

2016-Now	Teaching Assistant(Tulane U)	New Orleans, LA
	Arranged students in-class participation and ex	ams with class size
	ranging from 40-190; Answered course-related of fice hour	questions during of-
2012-2014	General Executive Officer(Northeastern U) Organized graduate students meetings	Boston, MA

2009-2010 Academic Assistant(Shanghai Ocean U) Shanghai, China Provided academic assistant for the Class of 2013 (class size: 100)

#### Leadership and Service

2010-2011	President	
	College Technology and Innovation Center	Shanghai, Chin

-Assisted students from the School of Economics and Management

to apply for research funding; -Organized fund raising campaign

2011 Volunteer Team Leader

> 14th FINA World Championships Shanghai, China

> -Responsible for scheduling itinerary and events management for

athletes from China, USA, Italy, Greece;

-Award: Excellent Volunteer of the Championships

2010 Volunteer Team Leader

> World Expo 2010 Shanghai, China

> -Award: Volunteer Star & Outstanding Volunteer of 2010 World EXPO